<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Peter Yates</title>
    <link href="https://peteryates.net/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://peteryates.net" />
    <updated>2022-03-18T11:21:53+11:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Peter Yates</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://peteryates.net</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Notre Dame History Project</title>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Yates</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://peteryates.net/notre-dame-history-project/"/>
        <id>https://peteryates.net/notre-dame-history-project/</id>
            <category term="History"/>

        <updated>2022-03-18T11:21:53+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>This is my Notre Dame history project, which I made in Febuary 2022, for the first assessment task of year 8.</p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This is my Notre Dame history project, which I made in Febuary 2022, for the first assessment task of year 8.</p>

<figure class="post__video"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="314" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-fvhxUAAz6U" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></figure>
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<p>Notre Dame de Paris, which translates to ‘Our lady of Parisʼ is an icon of the medieval world in Paris, France. Letʼs take a deeper look at the features of Notre Dame. Notre Dame was constructed on the site of an early christian church, the Cathedral of Saint-Étienne, in 1160, when the Bishop of Paris decided to build a larger, Gothic style church.<br>Now, letʼs move on to the Physical Features of the cathedral. Notre Dameʼs flying buttresses were built in 1200, to help support the roof and keep the Cathedral structurally sound. Because of the immense weight of the roof, the walls had to be thicker than a normal cathedral, and couldnʼt have large windows. Flying buttresses remedied this by spreading the weight of the roof onto pillars outside the main hall of the cathedral. Notre Dameʼs gargoyles were built to ward off demons and evil spirits from churchgoers, but also have an important role in draining water from the roof of the cathedral. The traditional draining system of the time, with water running down the walls of cathedral, would eventually erode the walls of the building and would not withstand over time. Notre Dame uses a system where water is caught from the gutters on the roof, and flows through the hollowed-out flying buttresses. At the end of the flying buttresses, gargoyles are mounted, and are designed so the flowing water appears to come out of the mouths of the creatures.<br>The three largest stained glass windows in Notre Dame, also known as the rose windows, named after their petal shape, are one of the most well-known aspects of the cathedral. The south window has 94 circles arranged in the shape of a flower, with each depicting a scene from the bible, as well as variants saint and martyrs of France. Notre Dameʼs Interior features a seating capacity of 9,000 people, with the standard nave and apse of a church of that timeframe. The cathedral also housed 10 bells, which throughout the middle ages have rung the time, call to prayer, as well as significant events such as the crowning of a new king. A number of significant catholic religious leaders have been laid to rest in the cathedral, including notable bishops and archbishops of Paris.<br>The cathedral also featured numerous christian relics, including the Crown of Thorns, which is what Jesus alledgedly wore on the cross, as well as a nail from the same cross.<br>Notre Dame featured one of the largest organs of the age, built by Frédéric Schambantz in 1403, which featured over 8,000 pipes. Notre Dame was an icon of its time, and even after the devastating fire in 2019, will still be an incredible example of art and engineering of the middle ages.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
